Harsh Mohan Gajra - Software Engineer (AWS)

Seattle, WA, USA 98104 | 607-338-8922 | harsh.gajra@gmail.com

Objective

Software engineer with 5+ years of solid experiences, working for software development teams of industry cloud leaders like Amazon Web services (AWS) and early engineering teams at startups like Pype (acquired by AutoDesk). Highly experienced in all aspects of software development lifecycle and project management, from concept through development to delivery. Consistently recognized as a competent software engineer, with hard technical as well soft skills, required for coordinating cross-functional teams in a fast-paced environment to steer timely project completion. Armed with a Master's in computer science from State University of New York, I am looking forward to earning the position of Software Engineer at a leading organization, to utilize my skills in software development to develop high value software products.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/harsh-gajra/ **GitHub**: https://github.com/HarshGajraSUNY

Work Experience

Software Engineer - Amazon Web Services, Data Migration Service (https://aws.amazon.com/dms)
Seattle, Washington (Sept,2021 – now)

- Worked on designing and developing a Distributed Test Execution platform, that can manage and execute
 hundreds of test cases in parallel using serverless technologies like AWS Lambda, AWS Simple Workflow, AWS
 CloudWatch, Cloud development Kit and Java 11, to test different components AWS Data Migration Service like
 Control Plane, Data Plane and Platform.
- Started as 1st hire on the Platform STP team, helped grow the team to 6 software engineers, and served as subject matter expert for multiple components of the software product.
- Collaborated with a team of 6 engineers and product managers to scope the requirements, perform design reviews and deliver the requested features across the platform.
- Mentored and lead a team of 3 interns and 2 engineers to understand the framework in detail, map out the scope of user stories, performed code reviews and helped in design of features for development.
- Wrote CI/CD pipelines using AWS Cloud development kit and CloudFormation to perform infrastructure deployments predictably and repeatedly, with rollback on error.
- Worked on re-architecting the Canary and Test infrastructure to eliminate deployment bottlenecks and congestions leading to overall stabilization and faster deployments saving 50 hours a week.
- Designed and developed features, provided support and maintenance for the existing legacy monolithic testing framework, to test AWS Database Migration Service using Java 8, Spring boot framework and AWS RDS.
- Wrote automation, identified and eliminated bugs, fixed design flaws across the product stack concerning AWS DMS bringing down on call support tickets by 60 % and saving 2400 hours yearly.
- Actively managed, improved, and monitored cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2, S3, and RDS, including backups, patches, and scaling

Software Developer 2 – FINRA

Reston, Virginia (May 2020 - Sept, 2021)

- Contributed to the design and development of FINRA's Consolidated Audit Trail project using technologies like Java, AWS stack consisting of Cloud Formation, Lambda, EC2 and S3.
- Wrote SQL queries using Postgres on Amazon RDS to pull the required data to develop reports relating to Equities
 and Options traded on various stock exchanges that were displayed for the FINRA's Consolidated Audit Trail
 Project dashboards.
- Interfaced with cross functional team of product managers, software developers and business analysts to determine requirement specifications and negotiate product deliverables.
- Contributed code, design and documentation for a fraud detection product developed by FINRA for full lifecycle management of stock trades across different stock exchanges.

Software Engineer - Pype Inc (Acquired by AutoDesk in 2020)

Herndon, VA, USA (July 2018 – May 2020)

- Backend software engineering, design and Development of new features using microservices for web applications using Java 8, Jersey JAX-RS REST API framework, Spring Boot, and MySQL as the database.
- Designing and developed internal software solutions for optimizing the business process followed by in-house Sales and Support teams thus saving the organization \$360,000 per year in costs and 15,000 man-hours per year.
- Full Stack development of a document management and turnover package software application using Angular 6, HTML, CSS on frontend (20%) and Java 8, Jersey REST API framework on backend (80%) and MySql as database.
- Designed the data model and developed the backend code for an Email Cadence software tool using Java 8, Spring Boot, JPA and MySQL database.
- Designed applications using the message brokers like RabbitMQ for message queuing and asynchronous job processing.
- Algorithm Development: Design, Analyze and implement algorithms in core Java for solving various use cases across the software products of the company.
- Developed, implemented and/or improved the application production support knowledge management repository to ensure all are documented, process & procedures are clear and periodic reviews are conducted.
- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins and GitLab.
- Researched and developed proof of concepts, for developing new products using Google cloud console, AWS, GIMP and Java 8.
- Wrote automations for the manual tasks performed by Customer Support and Success Teams saving our 1000 hours/year in the process.

Education

Masters in Computer Science - State University Of New York, Binghamton, August 2016 - May 2018

Bachelor of Computer Engineering - K.J.Somaiya College of Engineering, Mumbai ,First class (2011- 2015)

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Object Oriented Programming Languages, Design Patterns.

Technical Skills

Java 8 / 11 Amazon Web Services GitHub

Spring Boot Brazil Cloud Development kit

GitJIRARDSPostgresMySQLDynamoDBAWS Systems ManagerSWFAWS LambdaCI/CDEC2AWS Cloudwatch

Paper Publications

- Paper: Credit card Fraud Detection and Prevention Using Perceptron Training Algorithm.
- **Journal:** International Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication, Apr 2015 **Link**: https://ijritcc.org/index.php/ijritcc/article/view/4182/4182